Hello friends, my name is Unnat Biradar,
welcome to my channel. Today we are going to
discuss a very important subject. We are going to
talk about it,
that subject is crop
insurance. We all know that health
insurance is life insurance, but this is
crop insurance. We will discuss what crop insurance is.
See, now we
know that life insurance means if
something happens to our life, then we get
money for it
and after that, if there is a health insurance, we all
know that if something happens to our health, if we fall
ill and have to take medicine, then
we get money for it. Similarly, if
something saves our crop, then the farmer
gets money for it. It is
called crop insurance. Every year the farmer has to face a lot of hardships and has to
bear the consequences, the crop suffers huge
losses. That is why the government has made a crop insurance scheme, we will
discuss about it.
Hello friends,
we will discuss about the crop insurance scheme, so this is the PM Crop Insurance
Scheme, the Prime Minister Crop Insurance Scheme. So now
see, in this, it is implemented in all the 27 states and
union territories.  Meaning
implementation ghee subscription means those
farmers who subscribe to it means from the bank, it means
skin and those who do not subscribe
means they can come if they want, so like this
and the third appointment of
subscription means obscene, those people have to pay a lot of
Ishwari premium and the
balance premium is equally shared
between the State Government and Central Government, so this is such a scheme
also, now we will see about it and
how it is implemented, it
means e-tenders are issued, its bidding
process takes place, the companies which are
listed on the portal, the companies which give higher rates for each crop are
selected,
according to them their reach is scanned,
in which district, which
company is operational, the tender process is done accordingly,
after that enrollment and fee is given in it,
after that lock cement
and definition of state, all the insurance companies, that is, the
insurance company, it completes,
how much does it mean, there is a problem in it,
after that ghee means if the
flight happens  So how much has it earned, there is a
complete competition on the basis of that, that is, there is a
profit, after that the
time click flame is to pay on time,
this is very important for the Hero company,
now the crop insurance scheme subscription appointed from the school, the
company has
completely subscribed to my channel in this, the
subscription at the district level is also complete,
apart from the subscription, master notification,
all these different subscriptions mean
in the post, when the rules and responsibilities at the district level are
also there,
Robert has decided them here, now
what are these achievements, we will see, see,
it is very good, there are a lot, till now,
which was 22% earlier, now the school can take it from home,
you can subscribe to technology interventions, you had
not subscribed to it yet, the sum of real time data in that has caused a
loss of subscription money, you need to
address it on the basis of remote sensing technology, Airtel data,
because many times the
support of such people is
not in real time, that is why it has been
appointed in it that by using technology
like subscribe through farmer app, the
government  Do
n't forget to subscribe to Cotton Shankar at the international level. You
must subscribe. After that, Aadhar card has been
made for the people. You can register through the Common Service Centre.
Or after this, we will see the
process flow of money from the application. The
loan that I have taken now, its juice is for
agriculture operation. The
bank in it and the
Kisan Credit that people take, they have to guarantee it for this function.
After this, in the video,
I will tell you how this process is.
In the procedure for application, there will be complete
real-time subscriber data entry. After that, there will be
verification of application and
generation of application number.
After that, you will be directly
appointed. So, you can do this application yourself
or you can subscribe.
Where is the claim settlement done for the loss that you have suffered?
Claim settlement is also done online.
Many times, the money for the claim process
comes directly to your account, but a
report for it has to be submitted to the government, only
after that you will get the claim.  If you get the
settlement, then I have given this process,
provision of proof from
application, you have to apply for it,
then later if you do
not get it on time, you have to pay 12% interest on the screen,
this is also a very important
point, you can definitely subscribe to this channel, if
something goes wrong in this, you can subscribe to the channel, at the
district level, penalty entry, there are
many technical support calamity
interest areas, companies are doing claim settlement very well right now, no
account of it has been given, which is being done, what should be done for this is done
with the insurance company, the
subscription is completed with the meeting with them, please subscribe,
I have subscribed
here, you can subscribe here, you have
used it very well, so friends, this
means subscribe in the next video in school, you can do
TV show and secondly, there is an app,
how can you do it through its app,
we will discuss this also, so thank
you for watching this video, friends,
please subscribe to my YouTube channel
and in the comment section, if you have any
questions about the app  You must write that, thank you.